<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CAD on  </title>
    <link>https://keirancantilina.github.io/tags/cad/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CAD on  </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://keirancantilina.github.io/tags/cad/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Giant Wind Chimes</title>
      <link>https://keirancantilina.github.io/project/giant-windchimes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keirancantilina.github.io/project/giant-windchimes/</guid>
      <description>Timeline Sept 2017
Project Description Very large windchimes made using scrapped 6061-T6 1.5&amp;rdquo; aluminum square tubing. AutoDesk Inventor&amp;rsquo;s FEA utility was used to calculate the exact dimensions required for the desired pitch, so only a single hacksaw cut was necessary for each chime without any fine-tuning afterwards.
These windchimes are designed to have EXTREMELY long sustain (&amp;gt;30 sec) and very quiet odd-numbered harmonics. They produce a constant hum even when there is very little wind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musical Rocket Bells</title>
      <link>https://keirancantilina.github.io/project/rocket-bells/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keirancantilina.github.io/project/rocket-bells/</guid>
      <description>Timeline July 2017
Project Background One day, my friend Dane told me about a dream he had. It was long and convoluted (as dreams often are), but the part that stuck out to me was a scene he described where I ran around a space rocket nozzle factory playing the nozzles like bells.
As a person that plays real non-dream bells semi-professionally, I became intensely curious: how exactly would it sound if I was in a rocket nozzle factory playing the nozzles like bells?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultimate Deathtrap: The Danger Scooter</title>
      <link>https://keirancantilina.github.io/project/electric-scooter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keirancantilina.github.io/project/electric-scooter/</guid>
      <description>Timeline Feb 2017 - Current
Project Description This project was spawned by a desire to make my daily commute to class faster. Being a poor grad student, paying for a campus parking pass was out of the question. I could have bought a bike, but when I found an old 80s kick scooter on Craigslist, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist the temptation to build something ridiculous.
Project Description The build is fairly simple: a brushless hubmotor+wheel rescued from a dumpster replaces the rear wheel of the scooter.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>