<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on  </title>
    <link>https://keirancantilina.github.io/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on  </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://keirancantilina.github.io/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Musical Rocket Bells</title>
      <link>https://keirancantilina.github.io/project/rocket-bells/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keirancantilina.github.io/project/rocket-bells/</guid>
      <description>Timeline July 2017
Project Background My friend Dane emailed me one day to tell me about a dream he had. It was a long and convoluted (as dreams often are), but the part that stuck out to me was a scene he described where I ran around a space rocket nozzle factory playing the nozzles like bells.
As a person that plays real non-dream bells semi-professionally, I became intensely curious: how exactly would it sound if I was in a rocket nozzle factory playing the nozzles like bells?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GOES-16 Image Fetcher and Desktop Background Utility</title>
      <link>https://keirancantilina.github.io/project/goes16-fetch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keirancantilina.github.io/project/goes16-fetch/</guid>
      <description>Timeline Oct 2017
Project Description As an appreciator of both pretty pictures and ambitious radio projects, I wanted a real-time &amp;ldquo;Blue Marble&amp;rdquo;-style picture of the Earth as my deskop background.
My first attempt at making this happen was to try to receive the downlink from the GOES-16 geostationary weather satellite. GOES-16 is very far from the Earth, so a high-gain directional antenna is needed to listen in on it. Any reasonable person would have gotten a dish antenna, but given my time and budget constraints, I attempted to use an RTL-SDR with an inconveniently-sized corner reflector antenna built out of cardboard and foil, sized for the required gain at ~1600 Mhz.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>