<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on  </title>
    <link>https://keirancantilina.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on  </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://keirancantilina.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Giant Wind Chimes</title>
      <link>https://keirancantilina.github.io/project/giant-windchimes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keirancantilina.github.io/project/giant-windchimes/</guid>
      <description>Timeline Sept 2017
Project Description Very large windchimes made using scrapped 6061-T6 1.5&amp;rdquo; aluminum square tubing. AutoDesk Inventor&amp;rsquo;s FEA utility was used to calculate the exact dimensions required for the desired pitch, so only a single hacksaw cut was necessary for each chime without any fine-tuning afterwards.
These windchimes are designed to have EXTREMELY long sustain (&amp;gt;30 sec) and very quiet odd-numbered harmonics. They produce a constant hum even when there is very little wind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long-Distance Relationship Light</title>
      <link>https://keirancantilina.github.io/project/long-distance-light/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keirancantilina.github.io/project/long-distance-light/</guid>
      <description>Timeline May 2018
Project Background A few weeks before my wife and I were to be apart for the summer (due to me studying abroad and her only able to join me there in the fall), my wife stumbled upon these &amp;ldquo;Long Distance Friendship Lamps.&amp;rdquo; I loved the idea, but I was less enthusiastic about the fact that the operation of the lamps depended on the continuous operation of the company servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GOES-16 Image Fetcher and Desktop Background Utility</title>
      <link>https://keirancantilina.github.io/project/goes16-fetch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keirancantilina.github.io/project/goes16-fetch/</guid>
      <description>Timeline Oct 2017
Project Description As an appreciator of both pretty pictures and ambitious radio projects, I wanted a real-time &amp;ldquo;Blue Marble&amp;rdquo;-style picture of the Earth as my deskop background.
My first attempt at making this happen was to try to receive the downlink from the GOES-16 geostationary weather satellite. GOES-16 is very far from the Earth, so a high-gain directional antenna is needed to listen in on it. Any reasonable person would have gotten a dish antenna, but given my time and budget constraints, I attempted to use an RTL-SDR with an inconveniently-sized corner reflector antenna built out of cardboard and foil, sized for the required gain at ~1600 Mhz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultimate Deathtrap: The Danger Scooter</title>
      <link>https://keirancantilina.github.io/project/electric-scooter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keirancantilina.github.io/project/electric-scooter/</guid>
      <description>Timeline Feb 2017 - Current
Project Description This project was spawned by a desire to make my daily commute to class faster. Being a poor grad student, paying for a campus parking pass was out of the question. I could have bought a bike, but when I found an old 80s kick scooter on Craigslist, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist the temptation to build something ridiculous.
The build is fairly simple: a brushless hubmotor+wheel rescued from a dumpster replaces the rear wheel of the scooter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portrait Printing Typewriter</title>
      <link>https://keirancantilina.github.io/project/portrait-typewriter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keirancantilina.github.io/project/portrait-typewriter/</guid>
      <description>Timeline Aug 2017 - Sept 2017
Project Description This project began when I picked up a sad typewriter with a broken keyboard set out for free in front of the university library. Since I have a soft spot for obsolete technology, I gave it a new home. Repurposing it became a recreational exercise in both hardware-microcontroller and microcontroller-computer interfaces.
Images are broken down into lines of text by a Python script on a laptop, which then sends lines of ASCII via a serial-USB interface to an Arduino-style microcontroller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contactless Water Conductivity Sensor</title>
      <link>https://keirancantilina.github.io/project/conductivity-sensor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keirancantilina.github.io/project/conductivity-sensor/</guid>
      <description>Timeline Jan 2017 - Jun 2018
Project Description This project was for my Masters thesis at the University of Minnesota. The objective of this project was to develop a cheap and more rugged alternative to conventional water conductivity sensors, which are often susceptible to corrosion and fouling despite being quite expensive. This flaw exists because water conductivity is conventionally inferred by measuring the electrical resistivity of the water, which requires the direct contact of metallic electrodes with the water under test.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Scanmera</title>
      <link>https://keirancantilina.github.io/project/scanmera/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keirancantilina.github.io/project/scanmera/</guid>
      <description>Timeline Nov 2017 - Current
Project Description This project began as a just-for-fun repurposing of an obsolete scanner, but I soon discovered that the linear CCD in this scanner is very sensitive to near-infrared (NIR) wavelengths. This sensitivity, along with the high resolution of images produced by the Scanmera, means that I can potentially use it to measure the health of crops in fields by measuring the Normalized Difference Vegetation Index (NDVI), which is based on relative Red/IR reflectivity of plants.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>